Inventory of the George Loft Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
George Loft Papers
1957-1989
2006C21
Loft, George.
11 manuscript boxes (4.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, interview summaries, printed matter, and photographs, relating to American Friends Service Committee activities in Africa, especially relating to housing in Zambia; international development projects in Africa; and political and social conditions in Zambia, Zimbabwe and elsewhere in Africa.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research. Access to audiovisual materials requires at least two weeks advance notice. Audiovisual materials include sound recordings, video recordings, and motion picture film. Hoover staff will determine whether use copies of the materials requested can be made available. Some materials may not be accessible even with advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives Audiovisual Specialist for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2005.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1915 January 27 Born, New York City
1931 Graduated, High School of Commerce, New York
1932-1942 Assistant to Economist, National Dairy Products Corporation, New York
1938 Graduated, Bachelor's degree in Accounting, New York University
1940 Completed Master of Business Administration, New York University
1942 Married Eleanor Riddle
1942-1945 Chief of Subsistence Requirements Section, Military Planning Division, Office of the Quartermaster General, Washington, D.C.
1945-1947 Executive Assistant to Director, Frozen Food Foundation, Inc., Syracuse, N.Y.
1948 January-May Legislative Representative, Friends Committee on National Legislation, Washington, D.C.
1948-1953 Associate Public Relations Secretary, American Friends Service Committee, Philadelphia
1953-1957 Director, Public Relations, Atlas Chemical Industries, Wilmington, Delaware
1957-1960 Representative in Sub-Saharan Africa, American Friends Service Committee, based in Salisbury, Southern Rhodesia
1960-1961 Advisor on African Programs, American Friends Service Committee, Philadelphia
1961-1963 Director, Quaker Program at the United Nations, American Friends Service Committee
1963-1966 Vice President, African-American Institute, New York
1966 November-December Consultant, United Nations Development Program, Malawi
1967-1977 Employed by Field Foundation, New York
1969 July-September Consultant, American Friends Service Committee, Kafue Self-help Housing Project, Zambia
1971 February Consultant, American Friends Service Committee, Kafue Self-help Housing Project, Zambia
1972 September-October Special Mission to Rhodesia, with Eleanor Loft, on behalf of Friends Service Council, London, and American Friends Service Committee
1974-1979 Special Representative, African Service Programs and International Programs, American Friends Service Committee
1975 Consultant, American Friends Service Committee, Kafue Self-help Housing Project, Zambia
1976 Attended Rhodesia Conference, held in Geneva, as member of Quaker Rhodesia Conference group
Scope and Content of Collection
The George Loft Papers, acquired in 2005, document the activities of Quaker activist Loft and his wife Eleanor in southern Africa from the late 1950s through the 1970s. Initially the Lofts were sent by the American Friends Service Committee (AFSC) to the Federation of Rhodesia and Nyasaland in 1958, where George Loft was appointed to be the AFSC's Special Representative for Sub-Saharan Africa, and was based in Salisbury (Harare), Southern Rhodesia.
In this role, Loft served as an intermediary between the British colonial governments in that region and African nationalist leaders. In doing this, the AFSC hoped to foster non-violent social and political change in the region. During this period many African nationalist leaders were imprisoned, and as Loft visited them, he often brought books and news from the families of detainees, and sought to advocate on their behalf before government leaders. Much of the Correspondence dates from this period, and documents Loft's close contacts with government leaders such as Colonial Secretary Iain Macleod, former Southern Rhodesian Governor Garfield Todd, former Governor of Northern Rhodesia Sir Evelyn Hone, and Sir Robert Tredgold, Chief Justice of the Federation High Court. This series also contains correspondence with African nationalist leaders such as Kenneth Kaunda and Hastings K. Banda, who later were long-time presidents of the independent countries of Zambia and Malawi, respectively.
Upon returning to the United States in 1960, Loft continued to work with the AFSC, initially as a full-time employee and later as a consultant on specific projects, most often related to southern Africa. The Subject File documents some of the specific projects and development programs that Loft was involved with in various parts of Africa, most notably in Zambia, where his friendship with President Kaunda and many of his governmental ministers stretched back to their time as detainees under the colonial government. Loft made several trips to Zambia as a consultant on an AFSC project to provide housing for urban squatters, and networked with a wide array of European aid organizations and foundations to obtain funding for such programs.
During the 1970s, as the movement accelerated to bring about black majority rule in Rhodesia, Loft found himself drawn back to the country where he had earlier lived. Because of his connections with many nationalist leaders, such as Joshua Nkomo, Robert Mugabe, Bishop Abel Muzorewa, Rev. Ndabaningi Sithole, and a number of others, the AFSC sent him to Rhodesia in 1972 in the hope that his mediating influence could help bring the white minority government back to the negotiating table with these leaders. Loft joined a team of other Quakers from the U.S. and Britain at the Rhodesia Conference that was held in Geneva in 1976, and met informally with many of these leaders once again during the conference, hoping to help further a peaceful settlement that would lead to black majority rule. These activities are also documented in the Subject File.
In addition, the Photographs contain color photographic slides made by Loft documenting his work in Africa, with the strongest representation being from the years 1959-1964, and also of aid and development projects in Zambia and in the West African country of Mali in the early to mid 1970s.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: Correspondence, Subject File, and Photographs.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
American Friends Service Committee.; Technical assistance--Africa.; Housing--Zambia.; Zambia.; Zimbabwe.; Malawi.
Container List
- Correspondence, 1957-1998. (Box 1)
  Letters to and from African nationalist and governmental leaders, British colonial officials, American diplomats and aid workers, and officials within the American Friends Service Committee and the Friends Service Council, London. Largely consists of typed notes describing meetings with individuals as well as correspondence with individuals, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent, followed by a smaller group of chronological correspondence files between Loft and the American Friends Service Committee headquarters in Philadelphia
  - General. Detainees, 1959-1960 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Alphabetical
    - A, 1958-1960 (Folder 1: 2)
    - African National Congress, 1958 (Folder 1: 3)
    - Alderson, Cecil, 1957-1958 (Folder 1: 4)
    - Armitage, Sir Robert, 1959-1960 (Folder 1: 5)
    - Ashton, Hugh, 1957-1966 (Folder 1: 6)
    - B, 1958-1966 (Folder 1: 7)
    - Banda, Aleke, 1959-1966 (Folder 1: 8)
    - Banda, Hastings K.
      - Correspondence with, 1958-1965 (Folder 1: 9)
      - Correspondence about, 1959-1963 (Folder 1: 10)
      - Memoranda of meetings with, 1958-1960 (Folder 1: 11)
    - Barton, Frank, 1957 (Folder 1: 12)
    - Benson, Sir Arthur, 1958-1959 (Folder 1: 13)
    - Bernard, Rev. Neil, 1958-1959 (Folder 1: 14)
    - Birmingham, Walter, 1958-1959 (Folder 1: 15)
    - Booth, Rev. Alan, 1962-1964 (Folder 1: 16)
    - Bottomley, Arthur G., 1964 (Folder 1: 17)
    - Brownrigg, Philip, 1969 (Folder 1: 18)
    - Bwanausi, Augustine, 1959-1966 (Folder 1: 19)
    - C, 1958-1965 (Folder 1: 20)
    - Cadbury Trust, 1974-1980 (Folder 1: 21)
    - Callaghan, James, 1959-1964 (Folder 1: 22)
    - Cameron, Colin, 1962-1965 (Folder 1: 23)
    - Campbell, Sir Jock, 1962-1965 (Folder 1: 24)
    - Chakuamba, Steve-George, 1958-1962 (Folder 1: 25)
    - Chakulya, Wilson, 1959-1960 (Folder 1: 26)
    - Chibambo, MacKinley, 1959 (Folder 1: 27)
    - Chikerema, Robert, 1959-1964 (Folder 1: 28)
    - Chinamano, Josiah, 1959-1976 (Folder 1: 29)
    - Chipembere, Henry B. M., 1959-1972 (Folder 1: 30)
    - Chirwa, Orton, 1960-1966 (Folder 1: 31)
    - Chisiza, Dunduza, 1959-1962 (Folder 1: 32)
    - Chisiza, Yatuta, 1959-1964 (Folder 1: 33)
    - Chitambala, Frank, 1959-1964 (Folder 1: 34)
    - Chitepo, Herbert, 1957-1962 (Folder 1: 35)
    - Chiume, M. W. K., 1958-1963 (Folder 1: 36)
    - Chokani, Willie, 1959-1998 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - Chona, Mainza, 1964-1965 (Folder 2: 2)
    - Clark, Kendall, 1958-1959 (Folder 2: 3)
    - Clutton-Brock, Guy, 1958-1966 (Folder 2: 4)
    - Cole, David, 1957-1958 (Folder 2: 5)
    - D, 1958-1960 (Folder 2: 6)
    - De Bunsen, Bernard, 1959-1960 (Folder 2: 7)
    - Dumbutshena, Enoch, 1958-1969 (Folder 2: 8)
    - E, 1960-1979 (Folder 2: 9)
    - Evangelische Zentralstelle für Entwicklungshilfe, e.V. (Bonn, W. Germany), 1975-1980 (Folder 2: 10)
    - F, 1958-1959 (Folder 2: 11)
    - Field, Winston, 1962-1964 (Folder 2: 12)
    - Finn, H. R., 1958-1959 (Folder 2: 13)
    - Foot, Sir Hugh, 1962-1969 (Folder 2: 14)
    - G, 1957-1966 (Folder 2: 15)
    - Garley, David, 1958-1960 (Folder 2: 16)
    - Gereta-Chirwa, D. S., 1959-1960 (Folder 2: 17)
    - Gondwe, Vincent, 1958-1965 (Folder 2: 18)
    - Greaves, Bruce, 1959 (Folder 2: 19)
    - Gwandzura, Zechariah, 1959 (Folder 2: 20)
    - H, 1957-1966 (Folder 2: 21)
    - Hadsel, Fred, 1958-1959 (Folder 2: 22)
    - Harding, John, 1974 (Folder 2: 23)
    - Henson, Roy, 1958-1959 (Folder 2: 24)
    - Hodgson, G. C. D., 1958-1959 (Folder 2: 25)
    - Hone, Sir Evelyn, 1959-1963 (Folder 2: 26)
    - Hooper, Mary-Louise, 1959 (Folder 2: 27)
    - Houser, George, 1959-1960 (Folder 2: 28)
    - Howard, Philip
      - 1958-1960 (Folder 2: 29)
      - 1963-1966 (Folder 2: 30)
      - 1967-1974 (Folder 2: 31)
      - 1975-1986 (Folder 2: 32)
    - I, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 3: 1)
    - Interchurch Coordination Committee for Development Projects (Netherlands), 1974-1979 (Folder 3: 2)
    - J, 1959-1960 (Folder 3: 3)
    - Jere, Harrington, 1983-1987 (Folder 3: 4)
    - Jones, Sir Glyn, 1960-1965 (Folder 3: 5)
    - K, 1957-1970 (Folder 3: 6)
    - Kalulu, Solomon, 1962-1975 (Folder 3: 7)
    - Kamanga, Reuben, 1963-1964 (Folder 3: 8)
    - Kamba, Walter, 1978-1980 (Folder 3: 9)
    - Kapwepwe, Simon, 1964-1965 (Folder 3: 10)
    - Kaunda, Kenneth
      - 1959 (Folder 3: 11)
      - 1960-1962 (Folder 3: 12)
      - 1963 (Folder 3: 13)
      - 1964 (Folder 3: 14)
      - 1965 (Folder 3: 15)
      - 1966-1967 (Folder 3: 16)
      - 1974-1979 (Folder 3: 17)
      - 1980-1989 (Folder 3: 18)
    - Kumtumanji, Gabriel, 1959 (Folder 3: 19)
    - L, 1957-1960 (Folder 3: 20)
    - Laycock, Handley, 1958 (Folder 3: 21)
    - Lewis, Mark, 1957-1958 (Folder 3: 22)
    - M, 1957-1975 (Folder 3: 23)
    - Mackay, Peter, 1962-1973 (Folder 3: 24)
    - Macleod, Iain, 1960-1965 (Folder 3: 25)
    - Madavo, Crispin, 1975 (Folder 3: 26)
    - Madzimbamuto, Daniel, 1959-1969 (Folder 3: 27)
    - Makata, Lawrence, 1959 (Folder 3: 28)
    - Makulu, Henry, 1958-1959 (Folder 3: 29)
    - Maluleke, Josias, 1960 (Folder 3: 30)
    - Masemola, Nathaniel, 1976 (Folder 3: 31)
    - Matthews, Peter, 1957-1958 (Folder 3: 32)
    - Mawema, Michael, 1967-1976 (Folder 3: 33)
    - Mbekiani, Jasper, 1959 (Folder 3: 34)
    - Mbekiani, Wales (Nyemba), 1959-1964 (Folder 3: 35)
    - Mboya, Tom, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - McAdam, Albert, 1963 (Folder 4: 2)
    - Meier, Rhys, 1958-1966 (Folder 4: 3)
    - Mew, Ken, 1978 (Folder 4: 4)
    - Micklem, Lorna, 1959 (Folder 4: 5)
    - Mkandawire, Chiza, 1959 (Folder 4: 6)
    - Mnthambala, Augustine, 1958-1988 (Folder 4: 7)
    - Moffat, Sir John, 1959-1964 (Folder 4: 8)
    - Morris, Colin, 1958-1969 (Folder 4: 9)
    - Mpofu, Alfred, 1959 (Folder 4: 10)
    - Msika, Joseph, 1959-1980 (Folder 4: 11)
    - Msonthi, John, 1959-1966 (Folder 4: 12)
    - Mtandwa, Peter, 1960-1974 (Folder 4: 13)
    - Mugabe, Robert and Sally, 1967-1980 (Folder 4: 14)
    - Muhsin, Ali, 1959-1963 (Folder 4: 15)
    - Mulikita, Fwanyanga, 1971 (Folder 4: 16)
    - Mundia, Nalumino, 1964-1981 (Folder 4: 17)
    - Murphy, Richard, 1957-1974 (Folder 4: 18)
    - Murray-Parker, May, 1960 (Folder 4: 19)
    - Mushonga, Paul and Evelin, 1959 (Folder 4: 20)
    - Musukwa, A. S., 1959 (Folder 4: 21)
    - Mutasa, Didymus, 1958-1973 (Folder 4: 22)
    - Muvuti, Benjamin, 1972 (Folder 4: 23)
    - Muzorewa, Bishop Abel T., 1976 (Folder 4: 24)
    - Mwale, Siteke, 1975-1976 (Folder 4: 25)
    - Mwanakatwe, John, 1964-1965 (Folder 4: 26)
    - N-O, 1957-1978 (Folder 4: 27)
    - Newhati, Francis, 1959 (Folder 4: 28)
    - Nixon, Richard M., 1960 (Folder 4: 29)
    - Nkomo, Joshua, 1959-1980 (Folder 4: 30)
    - Noak, Hans, 1957-1959 (Folder 4: 31)
    - NORAD (Norwegian Aid), 1975-1980 (Folder 4: 32)
    - NOVIB Foundation (Netherlands), 1974 (Folder 4: 33)
    - Nyandoro, George, 1959-1979 (Folder 4: 34)
    - Nyerere, Julius, 1959-1960 (Folder 4: 35)
    - Nyimba, Opperson, 1958 (Folder 4: 36)
    - Ostrander, Taylor, 1959 (Folder 4: 37)
    - P, 1957-1976 (Folder 4: 38)
    - Padmore, George, 1958-1959 (Folder 4: 39)
    - Palley, Ahrn, 1962-1966 (Folder 4: 40)
    - Palmer, Joseph, 1958-1969 (Folder 4: 41)
    - Paradis, Ronald, 1960 (Folder 4: 42)
    - Pardey, H. G., 1958 (Folder 4: 43)
    - Parry, Hugh, 1959-1963 (Folder 4: 44)
    - Paton, Alan, 1962-1967 (Folder 4: 45)
    - Pifer, Alan, 1957 (Folder 4: 46)
    - Potter, Philip, 1959 (Folder 4: 47)
    - Prain, Sir Ronald, 1957-1969 (Folder 4: 48)
    - Pretorius, J. L., 1959-1965 (Folder 4: 49)
    - R, 1957-1960 (Folder 4: 50)
    - Radley, Philip, 1958-1959 (Folder 4: 51)
    - Rao, P. J., 1958 (Folder 4: 52)
    - Rennie, Sir Gilbert, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - Rhodes, Willard, 1958 (Folder 5: 2)
    - Rubadiri, David and Gertrude, 1963-1998 (Folder 5: 3)
    - S, 1957-1984 (Folder 5: 4)
    - Senn, G. C., 1959-1980 (Folder 5: 5)
    - Shamuyarira, Nathan, 1962-1979 (Folder 5: 6)
    - SIDA (Swedish International Development Authority), 1975-1981 (Folder 5: 7)
    - Silundika, George, 1980 (Folder 5: 8)
    - Sipalo, Munukayumbwa, 1964 (Folder 5: 9)
    - Sithole, Edson, 1959 (Folder 5: 10)
    - Sithole, Rev. Ndabaningi, 1960-1966 (Folder 5: 11)
    - Sjöman, Vilgot, 1958 (Folder 5: 12)
    - Smith, George-Ivan, 1974-1975 (Folder 5: 13)
    - Smith, Leslie, 1959-1960 (Folder 5: 14)
    - Smyly, David and Veronica, 1958-1959 (Folder 5: 15)
    - Sonjo, A. Machila, 1959-1960 (Folder 5: 16)
    - Spivey, Ronald, 1959 (Folder 5: 17)
    - Steere, Loyd V., 1957-1959 (Folder 5: 18)
    - Stephens, Christopher and Alice, 1959 (Folder 5: 19)
    - Stewart, Joyce, 1958-1959 (Folder 5: 20)
    - Swart, Edward, 1958-1959 (Folder 5: 21)
    - T, 1957-1960 (Folder 5: 22)
    - Takawira, Leopold, 1962-1970 (Folder 5: 23)
    - Tatum, Lyle, 1962-1963 (Folder 5: 24)
    - Temple, Merfyn, 1957-1965 (Folder 5: 25)
    - Thompson, Jack, 1957-1960 (Folder 5: 26)
    - Thorne, F. T., 1958 (Folder 5: 27)
    - Todd, Garfield, 1959-1988 (Folder 5: 28)
    - Tredgold, Barbara, 1958-1985 (Folder 5: 29)
    - Tredgold, Sir Robert, 1962-1977 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Union Miniere du Haut Katanga, 1957 (Folder 6: 2)
    - V, 1958-1960 (Folder 6: 3)
    - Van der Merwe, Hendrik, 1984-1987 (Folder 6: 4)
    - Van Wyk, Fred J., 1979 (Folder 6: 5)
    - Vernon-Jackson, Hugh, 1975 (Folder 6: 6)
    - W, 1957-1979 (Folder 6: 7)
    - Welensky, Sir Roy, 1960 (Folder 6: 8)
    - Whitehead, Sir Edgar, 1958-1959 (Folder 6: 9)
    - Wilson, Anthony E., 1971-1977 (Folder 6: 10)
    - Wilson, Roger, 1959 (Folder 6: 11)
    - Wina, Arthur, 1964-1965 (Folder 6: 12)
    - Wina, Sikota, 1964 (Folder 6: 13)
    - Y, 1958 (Folder 6: 14)
    - Zvogbo, Eddison, 1973-1980 (Folder 6: 15)
  - Chronological
    - George Loft to AFSC Headquarters, Philadelphia
      - 1957 (Folder 6: 16)
      - 1958
        - January-May (Folder 6: 17)
        - June-December (Folder 6: 18)
      - 1959
        - January-May (Folder 6: 19)
        - July-December (Folder 6: 20)
      - 1960 (Folder 6: 21)
    - AFSC Headquarters, Philadelphia, to George Loft, 1957-1960 (Folder 6: 22)
- Subject File, 1958-1980. (Box 7)
  Correspondence, reports, memoranda, news clippings, pamphlets, government publications, minutes of meetings, and press releases, which primarily document American Friends Service Committee projects and initiatives related to Africa, and especially in the countries of Malawi, Mali, Zambia, and Zimbabwe (Rhodesia). Arranged alphabetically by name of country
  - General
    - All-African People's Conference, Accra, Ghana, 1958 (Folder 7: 1)
    - Fundraising trips to Europe and Africa, for AFSC sponsored projects
      - 1969 September (Folder 7: 2)
      - 1974 September-October (Folder 7: 3)
      - 1975 September-November (Folder 7: 4)
    - South Africa / Federation of Rhodesia and Nyasaland, trip report, George Loft and Louis Schneider, 1958 (Folder 7: 5)
    - Southern Africa reports from George Loft, 1958-1960 (Folder 7: 6)
  - Malawi
    - Cabinet crisis, 1964 (Folder 7: 7)
    - U.N. Development Program, special mission (1966)
      - Background information, 1966-1967 (Folder 7: 8)
      - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Folder 7: 9)
      - Itinerary and contacts list, 1966 (Folder 7: 10)
      - Reports
        - George Loft, 1966 (Folder 7: 11)
        - International Labor Organization, 1966 (Folder 7: 12)
        - United Nations Development Program, 1965-1966 (Folder 7: 13)
    - Government offices directory, 1974 (Folder 7: 14)
  - Mali
    - Drought relief project, 1974 (Folder 7: 15)
    - Drought relief project, 1975 (Folder 7: 16)
    - Photographs, relief projects, circa 1977 (Folder 7: 17)
  - Zambia / AFSC housing projects (Box 8)
    - Agreements with the Zambian government, 1967-1968 (Folder 8: 1)
    - Contact lists, 1967-1968 (Folder 8: 2)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1967-1974 (Folder 8: 3)
      - Bard McAllister, AFSC Zambia Field Director
        - 1967 (Folder 8: 4)
        - 1968 (Folder 8: 5)
        - 1969 (Folder 8: 6)
        - 1971 (Folder 8: 7)
      - Henry Passmore, AFSC Headquarters
        - 1967 (Folder 8: 8)
        - 1968 (Folder 8: 9)
        - 1969 (Folder 8: 10)
        - 1970 (Folder 8: 11)
        - 1971 (Folder 8: 12)
      - Zambian government
        - General, 1967-1970 (Folder 8: 13)
        - President Kenneth Kaunda, 1967-1970 (Folder 8: 14)
    - George Loft visits
      - 1967 (Folder 8: 15)
      - 1969
        - Correspondence and news reports, 1969 (Folder 8: 16)
        - News clippings and background information, 1969 (Folder 8: 17)
      - 1971
        - Background information
          - General, 1968-1971 (Folder 8: 18)
          - Kafue Housing Project, 1967-1971 (Folder 8: 19)
        - Correspondence
          - Contacts in Geneva, 1971 (Folder 8: 20)
          - Contacts in Zambia, 1971 (Folder 8: 21)
          - Other aid and development agencies, 1971 (Folder 8: 22)
        - Miscellany, 1971 (Folder 8: 23)
      - 1975 (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - Photographs, 1969-1977 (Folder 9: 2)
    - Publicity, 1970-1978 (Folder 9: 3)
    - Reports
      - "A View of the Kafue Squatter,", 1970 (Folder 9: 4)
      - "Chawama Self-Help Housing Project,", 1975 (Folder 9: 5)
  - Zimbabwe-Rhodesia
    - George and Eleanor Loft mission (September-October 1972)
      - Background material
        - Abel Muzorewa, pamphlets, 1972 (Folder 9: 6)
        - Government publications, Rhodesia
          - "Anglo-Rhodesian Relations,", 1971 (Folder 9: 7)
          - "Constitution,", 1969 (Folder 9: 8)
          - "Economic Survey of Rhodesia,", 1972 (Folder 9: 9)
        - Government publications, United Kingdom, Pearce Commission Report, 1972 (Folder 9: 10)
        - Justice for Rhodesia campaign, 1972 (Folder 9: 11)
        - Miscellany, 1969-1972 (Folder 9: 12)
      - Report, 1972
        - Part I (Folder 9: 13)
        - Part II (Folder 9: 14)
    - Rhodesia Conference, Geneva (October-December 1976) (Box 10)
      - Background material, 1976-1977 (Folder 10: 1)
      - Correspondence
        - Conference participants, 1976-1977 (Folder 10: 2)
        - Friends Service Council, London
          - Walter Martin, 1976-1977 (Folder 10: 3)
          - Others, 1976 (Folder 10: 4)
        - Trevor Jepson, 1976-1977 (Folder 10: 5)
        - Kenneth Kaunda, 1976 (Folder 10: 6)
        - Others, 1976 (Folder 10: 7)
      - Meeting minutes, Friends Service Council, London, Ad Hoc Group on Quaker Presence at Geneva Talks, 1976 (Folder 10: 8)
      - Meeting notes (George Loft, Trevor Jepson, Lyle Tatum), 1976 (Folder 10: 9)
      - Press clippings, 1976 (Folder 10: 10-11)
      - Press releases and position papers
        - African National Council, 1976 (Folder 10: 12)
        - Zimbabwe African National Union, 1976 (Folder 10: 13)
        - Other parties, 1976 (Folder 10: 14)
      - Weekly reports (George Loft, Trevor Jepson), 1976 (Folder 10: 15)
    - Friends Service Council / Quaker Peace and Service, London, 1978-1980 (Folder 10: 16)
    - London Conference, (1979) (Folder 10: 17)
    - Freedom House--Election monitoring, (1979)
      - Correspondence and press clippings, 1979 (Folder 10: 18)
      - Report, 1979 (Folder 10: 19)
    - News clippings
      - 1969 (Folder 10: 20)
      - 1974 (Folder 10: 21)
      - 1976-1977 (Folder 10: 22)
      - 1978-1980 (Folder 10: 23)
- Photographs, 1958-1979. (Box 11)
  Although there are a few photographic prints, the bulk of this series are color 35mm slides taken by Loft and documenting his work in southern Africa from 1958 to 1964, as well as the three All-African Conferences held between 1958 and 1961 in Accra, Tunis, and Cairo. Also included are photographs from trips during this period to Nigeria, Congo, Tanzania, and Senegal, as well as development projects in Mali and Zambia during the 1970s. Arranged by format, prints and slides, with slides arranged in groups A-L, representing events or subjects
  - Prints. (Folder 11: 1)
    Miscellaneous African leaders (Henry Chipembere, Kenneth Kaunda, Eduardo Mondland, Holden Roberto)
  - 35mm slides, taken by George Loft, 1958-1979 (Folder 11: 2)
    - List of individual slides, arranged by group
    - Group A: Third All-African People's Conference, Cairo, Egypt, March 1961
    - Group B: Second All-African People's Conference, Tunis, Tunisia, January 1960
    - Group C: First All-African People's Conference, Accra, Ghana, December 1958
    - Group D: Southern Rhodesia (Zimbabwe), 1959-1964
    - Group E: Northern Rhodesia / Zambia, 1957-1964
    - Group F: Nyasaland / Malawi, 1957-1964